

Passionate and driven Software Engineer with a specialization in Windows and VMware Infrastructure. I hope that the technology I create reflects my love for breeding innovation and breaking down complex problems to their very core.

# Work Experience \_\_

Fremont, California

SITE RELIABILITY ENGINEER - WINDOWS / VMWARE AUTOMATION

2020 - Present

- Selected by Sr. Directors to be placed into a newly developed team with the purpose of scaling Tesla's internal core infrastructure with the assistance of automation
- Tasked to develop, manage, and improve complex automation processes that are used to scale the companies Active Directory and VMWare infrastructure
- · Working with popular automation software like PowerShell and Python, I created highly advanced scripts and modules that automated processes that were previously slower and required high levels of human involvement
- Using additional automation frameworks such as Puppet, SCCM, and Splunk, I ensured processes were highly reliable, secure, and produced clean and usable logs
- My role required constant use of common DevOps tools and procedures such as Git, Jira, Bitbucket, Confluence, Clean Coding Techniques, and Proper Logging Procedures
- · Responsible for ongoing learning and testing of new applications and technologies to discover new possibilities for efficiency and automation

Tesla Fremont, California

IT SUPPORT TECHNICIAN

- Working under the IT Operations team for Tesla's 4,100+ servers and 59,000+ workstations
- Tasked to create and deploy internal support applications for Tesla servers that have a reach of 2,000+ clients
- Assisted with IT Support by completing over 5000+ support tickets and over 6000+ support calls
- Working in React, Diango, Python and PowerShell to create web applications that interface with Active Directory in a clean and secure manor
- My internal support applications help manage Tesla's 59,000+ employee's accounts and workstations globally

#### **US. Army Reserves (812th TIN-E Signal Company)**

Mare Island, California

25B INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY SPECIALIST

2017 - Present

2019 - 2020

- · Tasked to assist with the startup of a new Signal Company by training incoming soldiers and processing new equipment
- Assisted with training 300+ new soldiers with classroom and hands on courses
- Lead various teams of 10-25 soldiers during training and validation courses
- Tasked to design, build, maintain, and recover 45+ servers used in a Tactical Operations Center
- · Worked as one of the units Systems Administrators for multiple Windows and Linux environments
- Responsible for leading a team of 25+ soldiers to build a portable Tactical Operations Center while adhering to strict Department of Defense security restrictions
- Tasked to prioritize Security through multiple defense mechanisms on Confidential, SECRET, and TOP SECRET missions
- Managed an Operations Center that was used to connect over 2400+ soldiers globally using the WIN-T Tactical Warfighter Network

### **Education**

#### SECTA (Southeast Career and Technical Academy)

Las Vegas, Nevada Aug. 2013 - Jun. 2017

• High school student volunteering with the ECS department supporting the schools 1500+ workstations.

- Tasked to install, monitor, and maintain over 1500+ workstations, iPads, and laptops for teachers and students.
- While studying as a full time student, I worked to install and repair over 600+ workstations and assist over 1000+ students with credential and connectivity issues.

## Honors & Certificates

### **MILITARY**

The Army Commendation Medal, Combat Support Training Exercise (CSTX 91-18)

HQ, 505th TTSB Las Vegas, NV Washington DC, USA

2017 **SECRET Clearance**, Department of Defense

SETH SMITH · RÉSUMÉ AUGUST 1, 2021